<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dvid on Hugo</title>
    <link>https://hug0vincent.github.io/categories/dvid/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dvid on Hugo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 22:24:10 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hug0vincent.github.io/categories/dvid/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DVID : Characteristics 2</title>
      <link>https://hug0vincent.github.io/2019/10/dvid-characteristics-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 22:24:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hug0vincent.github.io/2019/10/dvid-characteristics-2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I recently bought a DVID board which is an open source vulnerable designed IoT device. In this post I will try to explain how to solve the third challenge of the DVID project. In this challenge we need to write data to a special characteristic.
Challenge Let&amp;rsquo;s flash the firmware, enable and setup the usb dongle:
     1
2
3
  sudo avrdude -c usbasp -p m328p -U flash:w:characteristics2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DVID : Characteristics</title>
      <link>https://hug0vincent.github.io/2019/10/dvid-characteristics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 10:28:41 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hug0vincent.github.io/2019/10/dvid-characteristics/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I recently bought a DVID board which is an open source vulnerable designed IoT device. In this post I will try to explain how to solve the second Bluetooth challenge of the DVID project. In this challenge we need to read data from a special characteristic.
Challenge Let&amp;rsquo;s flash the firmware, enable Bluetooth and setup the usb dongle:
     1
2
3
  sudo avrdude -c usbasp -p m328p -U flash:w:characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BLE introduction</title>
      <link>https://hug0vincent.github.io/2019/10/ble-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 14:23:07 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hug0vincent.github.io/2019/10/ble-introduction/</guid>
      <description>Introduction I recently bought a DVID board which is an open source vulnerable designed IoT device. In this post I will try to explain how the Bluetooth protocol works and how we can solve the first Bluetooth challenge of the DVID project.
Bluetooth protocol This talk is a good introduction to Bluetooth hacking, what&amp;rsquo;s following come from this document, but if you want more details you should read it. The next diagram shows how a typical connection between a phone and a Bluetooth device work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>